---
title: "How to Apply for a Canada Student Visa from Itahari: 2026 Complete Guide"
slug: "canada-student-visa-itahari-2026-guide"
date: "2026-03-31"
modified: "2026-03-31"
author: "Transit Education"
categories: ["Uncategorized"]
excerpt: "If you are a student in **Itahari, Dharan, Biratnagar**, or anywhere in **Sunsari and Koshi Province**, and you are planning to study in Canada, this guide is written specifically …"
draft: false
---

If you are a student in **Itahari, Dharan, Biratnagar**, or anywhere in **Sunsari and Koshi Province**, and you are planning to study in Canada, this guide is written specifically for you. This is not a generic national guide; it is built around the questions that students from eastern Nepal actually ask when starting their Canada study permit journey in **2026**.

Canada continues to be one of the most sought-after destinations for Nepali students. With globally recognised qualifications, post-graduation work opportunities, and a strong international student community, it is easy to understand why students from Itahari to Kathmandu are choosing Canada as their destination. However, the application process is longer and more detailed than most other countries. Students who plan early and work with experienced consultancies have a clear advantage.

### **Why Canada Is the Top Choice for Students from Itahari and Eastern Nepal**

Students from Sunsari, Morang, and the broader Koshi Province increasingly choose Canada over other English-speaking countries for the following reasons:

- Globally recognised academic degrees from Canadian universities and polytechnic colleges

- **Part-time work permission of up to 24 hours per week** during studies

- Post-Graduation Work Permit (PGWP) of up to 3 years after graduation

- Affordable study options through public colleges such as Lambton College and George Brown Polytechnic

- A welcoming and safe environment for Nepali students abroad

For students in Itahari who are weighing options between Australia, the UK, or Canada, the PGWP opportunity and the breadth of affordable diploma and degree programs make Canada a particularly strong choice in 2026.

### **Academic and English Requirements for Canadian Institutions**

Most Canadian universities and colleges have the following minimum entry requirements for Nepali applicants:

- **Minimum academic score:** 2.8 CGPA or 50 percent or higher in your most recent qualification

- **IELTS Academic:** Overall band 6.5 with no individual band below 6.0

- **PTE Academic:** Overall score of 60 with no band below 60

Some institutions and specific programs—especially engineering, health sciences, and business may require higher academic scores or have prerequisite subjects such as mathematics or biology. It is important to verify the exact requirements for your chosen course before applying.

### **Canada Study Permit Process from Nepal Step by Step (2026)**

The Canada study permit process has several stages. Understanding each step helps you plan your timeline properly, which is especially important for students in Itahari and eastern Nepal who may be starting this process for the first time.

**Step 1: Select your institution and program**** 
**Research universities and colleges that match your academic background, career goals, and budget.

**Step 2: Submit your application and documents**** 
**Submit your passport, academic certificates, letters of recommendation, CV, and statement of purpose to your chosen institution either directly or through **Transit Education Itahari.** Application fees range from approximately NPR 7,000 to NPR 27,000 depending on the institution.

**Step 3: Receive your offer letter**** 
**Offer letters typically arrive within one to three weeks for colleges. Once you have your offer, proceed to arrange your finances and apply for the No Objection Certificate (NOC).

**Step 4: Arrange finances and pay the tuition deposit**** 
**Canadian institutions typically require a tuition deposit of NPR 280,000 to one full year of tuition fees. At Transit Education Itahari, students are guided through loan options and sponsorship documentation from early stages.

**Step 5: Receive your Letter of Acceptance and Provincial Attestation Letter**** 
**The **Letter of Acceptance (LOA)** and **Provincial Attestation Letter (PAL)** are required documents for your study permit application. These are mandatory in 2026.

**Step 6: Apply for your Canada Study Permit**** 
**Apply online at canada.ca. **Note: In 2026, all Nepali students apply via the Regular Study Permit Stream as the SDS program has been discontinued.** The government study permit fee is CAD 150, and biometric fees are CAD 85.

### **Study Costs - Tuition and Living Expenses for Nepali Students**

Understanding the full cost of studying in Canada is critical for students and families in Itahari who are planning their finances.

- **Tuition fees:** Starting at approximately CAD 12,000 per year and higher depending on the institution.

- **Annual living costs:** The Government of Canada estimates **CAD 22,895 per year** for international students in 2026. This is the minimum amount you must demonstrate for your permit.

- **Cheaper cities:** Smaller cities such as Windsor, Sault Ste. Marie, and Fredericton tend to have significantly lower living costs.

At Transit Education Itahari, students are also guided on collateral-free education loan options available for certain top-tier Canadian universities including the University of Windsor, Brock University, and the University of New Brunswick.

### **Complete Document Checklist for Canada Study Permit from Nepal**

Having your documents ready and correctly organised is one of the most important steps. The following is the standard checklist for Nepali applicants:

- Valid passport

- All academic documents: SEE/SLC, High School (+2), Bachelor degree, and Masters if applicable

- Updated CV or resume and **detailed Statement of Purpose (SOP)**

- Two to three recommendation letters

- **Proof of funds:** GIC for **CAD 22,895** and education loan documents

- **Income evidence:** Tax clearance certificates of your financial sponsors

- **Letter of Acceptance (LOA) and Provincial Attestation Letter (PAL)**

- Medical examination results and Passport-sized photographs

- Canadian immigration forms including IMM 1294, IMM 5645E, and IMM 5707

### **Canada Visa Help for Students in Itahari, Sunsari, and Eastern Nepal**

At **Transit Education Itahari** located in the heart of Itahari students from Sunsari, Morang, Dharan, Biratnagar, and surrounding areas receive guidance specifically tailored to their situation. This includes help with financial document structuring, income formalisation advice, SOP writing, and complete application support.

Transit Education holds branches in Kathmandu, Itahari, Damak and Damauli, with a team that has guided hundreds of students through successful Canada study permit applications.

### **Frequently Asked Questions - Canada Student Visa from Itahari**

- **Which is the best consultancy in Itahari for Canada student visa?**** 
**Transit Education Itahari is widely regarded as one of the leading study abroad consultancies in Itahari for Canada student visa applications. With a dedicated team experienced in Canadian admissions and immigration, students from Sunsari and the broader Koshi Province receive end-to-end support including university selection, document preparation, SOP guidance, and visa filing.**

- How long does the Canada student visa take to process from Nepal?**** 
**Processing time typically ranges from two to twelve weeks. In 2026, students are advised to apply at least 4-6 months before their intake.**

- What is the minimum IELTS score required for Canada from Nepal?**** 
**Most Canadian institutions require a minimum IELTS Academic overall band of 6.5 with no individual band below 6.0. Some programs at certain universities may require a higher score. PTE Academic is also widely accepted with a minimum overall score of 60.**

- Can students from Itahari get an education loan for Canada without collateral?**** 
**Yes, collateral-free education loan options are available for select top-tier Canadian universities including the University of Windsor, Brock University, and the University of New Brunswick. These options are primarily for masters programs and are subject to academic eligibility requirements. Transit Education Itahari can help you assess whether you qualify and guide you through the process.**

- Is Canada a good choice for students from eastern Nepal compared to Australia or the UK?**** 
**Canada is strong due to the 3-year PGWP. Notably, as **Australia has classified Nepal as an Assessment Level 3 (High Risk) country in 2026**, Canada offers a more predictable path for many.**

- What is a Provincial Attestation Letter and why do I need it?**** 
**The Provincial Attestation Letter, or PAL, is a document required for most Canadian study permit applications following updated immigration policies. It is issued by the Canadian province where your institution is located and confirms that your spot is within the government-allocated quota for international students. Your institution will provide this letter once your enrollment is confirmed.**

- How much does it cost to study in Canada from Nepal?**** 
**Tuition starts at CAD 12,000, and living costs are set at **CAD 22,895** for 2026. Total annual costs typically range from CAD 35,000 to CAD 50,000.**

- Where is the Transit Education Itahari office located?**** 
**Transit Education is located in Itahari Sangit Chowk, Sunsari, serving students from Dharan, Biratnagar, and surrounding areas.**

### Final Thoughts**

Applying for a Canada student visa from Itahari or anywhere in eastern Nepal is entirely achievable with the right preparation. With the **discontinuation of SDS**, the focus is now on high-quality documentation and a strong SOP. At Transit Education, we ensure students receive personalised guidance at every stage of their journey.

