---
title: "10 Reasons why Finland is the best destination for Nepali students"
slug: "10-reasons-why-finland-is-the-best-destination-for-nepali-students"
date: "2025-04-01"
modified: "2025-04-01"
author: "Transit Education"
categories: ["Study Abroad"]
excerpt: "**High Quality Education**: Finland has one of the best education systems in the world, with a strong focus on practical learning and research. **Affordable or free education**: Pu…"
draft: false
---

## **10 Reasons Why Finland is the Best Destination for Nepali Students**

**High Quality Education**:

Finland has one of the best education systems in the world, with a strong focus on practical learning and research.

**Affordable or free education**:

Public universities offer scholarships to non-Eu students making it more affordable.

**Multicultural society:**

Finland welcomes international students and has a growing Nepali community.

**Work opportunities:**

Students can work up to 30 hours per week and earn to support their expenses.

**Internship & Industry connections**:

Students get hands-on experience through internships and collaborations with companies.

**Affordable living costs:**

Compared to other European countries, Finland offers student discounts on transport, food and housing.

**Opportunities for family settlement:**

Students who study and work in Finland can later bring their family members under dependent visa.

**Research opportunities:**

Universities offer excellent facilities for research in various fields, including technology and innovation.

**Strong job market:**

There is a demand for skilled workers, especially in IT, Engineering.

**Scholarships for International students:**

Many universities offer scholarships based on academic merit.
Get more info!Please enable JavaScript in your browser to complete this form.Name *FirstLastEmail *Contact Number * 
Submit

